https://www.metrx.com/privacy-policy/

Privacy Policy
Free 1-3 Day Delivery on Orders Over $85
|
How fast will I Receive My Order?
$0.00
Due to COVID-19, we are currently out of stock on products. We apologize for any inconvenience and hope to be back to fulfilling orders soon.
Privacy Policy
Print this Privacy Policy
Last Updated:  June 24, 2020
This Privacy Policy describes how The Nature's Bounty Co. and its subsidiaries including, without limitation, American Health Inc., Balance Bar Company, Best Bar Ever Inc., Dr. Organic Limited, The Ester-C Company, Home Health Products LLC, Met-Rx Substrate Technology Inc., Nature's Bounty (NY) Inc., Puritan's Pride Inc., Rexall Sundown Inc., Solgar Inc., United States Nutrition Inc., and Vita Health Products Inc. (collectively the "Company", "we", "us") collect and use personal information about you. It also describes the choices available to you regarding our use of your personal information and how you can access and update this information. By using the Company’s products or services, you agree to the collection, use, and disclosure of your information as described in this Privacy Policy. If you do not, please do not use the Company’s products or services.
European Union (EU) Residents:
Those living in the EU should also view the “Information Collected from Individuals in the European Union” section of this Privacy Policy to learn additional information about how we collect and use your personal information in compliance with EU data protection laws.
For the purposes of this Privacy Policy, personal information means information that either identifies, relates to, or describes you on its face, or that could reasonably be linked, directly or indirectly, with you or your household.
It is possible that third parties may be able to personally identify you by other means, including by associating facially anonymous information about your Internet activity with other records.
As provided in more detail below, we collect personal information from a variety of sources, including from:
Social media providers
Data aggregators
Public databases
Tracking technologies, and
From you directly.
If you have questions about this Privacy Policy or how we treat your personal information, please contact us using the information provided in the “How to Contact Us” section of this Privacy Policy.
Personal Information We Collect
Depending on how we interact with you, we may collect, use, store and transfer different types of personal information about you. This includes:
Identifiers, such as your name and title. We may also collect your birth date or gender, but only when you choose to provide us with that information, such as in a product review or your account settings.
Identifiers may also include:
Contact Information, such as your mailing address, billing address, email address, and telephone number(s).
Account Profile Information, such as your username or similar identifier, account password, purchase/order history, and your interests provided when signing up for your account.
Commercial Information, such as credit card, debit card, and other financial payment information.
Correspondence Information, including anything you may provide to us in your communications with us, such as your intended or actual use of our products, questions about our products, and records of your communications with us.
Health Information, specifically any adverse reaction you might have to one of our products and relevant health information that you choose to share with us.
Internet/Electronic Activity Information, such as your internet protocol ("IP") address; your web browser software and version; if you arrived at the services through a link from another website, information about the page you came from; your mobile device identifier and other information about devices you use to access the services. We also collect online activity information, such as information about your activity while using the services, including information we may gather through the use of cookies, web beacons and other similar tools that tell us which pages you choose to view, and queries you make using our "search" function. For more information about how and when we collect this information and what we do with it, please see the “Cookies and Tracking” section of this Privacy Policy.
Marketing and Communications Information, such as your preferences in receiving marketing, promotions and sales offers from us, and photographs containing images of you where you choose to provide us with them as part of a sweepstakes or contest.
Information Collected from Individuals Outside the United States
Our services are U.S. based and therefore, if you are using the services from outside the United States, including the European Union or European Economic Area, and provide us with personal information, please note that your personal information will be transferred, stored and processed in the United States using appropriate transfer mechanisms as required by applicable law. This is done either to ensure we are able to provide our services to you, or where not necessary for the provision of our services (such as in the case of providing you with marketing communications), it is done only with your consent. Please note, however, that the data protection laws in the United States may not be as comprehensive as those in your country of residence. We are, however, unable to provide our services without handling your personal information in the United States.
How We Collect Information About You and Sources of Personal Information
We collect information from you and about you in different ways.
Direct Interactions. We collect most of your personal information from you directly. For example, you may give us a variety of your Identifiers, Contact Information, Account Profile Information, Commercial Information, Correspondence Information, Health Information, Internet/Electronic Activity Information, and Marketing and Communications Information when you:
Create an account on one of our websites;
Purchase products from our website or by phone;
Contact us with questions or provide feedback about our products;
Subscribe to our mailing lists or otherwise agree to receive marketing communications from us; and
Enter competitions, promotions or surveys we run from time to time.
Automated technologies and interactions. As you interact with our websites, we may automatically collect Internet/Electronic Activity Information about your equipment, browsing actions and patterns. We collect this personal data by using cookies, web beacons, server logs and other similar technologies. We may also receive Internet/Electronic Activity Information about you if you visit other websites employing our cookies. Please see the “Cookies and Tracking” section of this Privacy Policy for further details.
Third parties or publically available sources. We may also collect information about you from third parties and commercially available sources, including from social media providers, data aggregators, and public databases. Please note that we may combine the various types of information we collect about you and use it as described in this Privacy Policy.
How We Use Your Information
We use your personal information for the following business purposes:
Contact Us. We use personal information such as your Contact Information to respond to your questions and comments when you communicate with us through links or pages provided by the services, such as the "Contact Us" feature.
Shopping. If you purchase products from us, we use personal information, such as your Contact Information and Commercial Information to process your purchase, confirm your order, and deliver the items to you. We also use cookies which are necessary for completing the online check-out process. For further information on our use of cookies, please see the “Cookies and Tracking” section of this Privacy Policy.
Administration. We use personal information to perform business analyses or for other purposes to improve the quality of our business, our services, and the products we offer. We may also use personal information about you to administer our services, including to investigate possible violations of and enforce our contracts, including our website Terms of Use and any terms and conditions associated with our products and services, and to comply with our legal obligations.
Fraud and Crime Prevention and Detection. We use your personal information, such as your Identifiers, Contact Information, and Internet/Electronic Activity Information, to help prevent and detect fraud and other crimes that might be committed using or against our services. We do this to both protect our legitimate interests in protecting our business assets and comply with our legal obligations.
IT Security and Website Operation. We use your personal information, such as your Internet/Electronic Activity Information, to help us protect our legitimate interests in troubleshooting, testing, maintaining, and protecting our IT systems, including this website.
Compliance with Legal and Regulatory Obligations. We use your personal information to comply with our legal and regulatory obligations, which arise from time to time. For instance, we may use your Contact Information to alert you if a product is recalled. We may also collect your Health Information to maintain records of adverse reactions to our dietary supplement products when you choose to provide this to us.
Also, if you have decided to opt in for marketing purposes, we may use your personal information for the following purposes:
Email Newsletters and Promotions. We use personal information about you, including your Contact Information, to send you our newsletters, information about our loyalty program, exclusive offers and promotions, and product news through email, where you have agreed to receive such communications. We also may use personal information about you to administer our promotions and our loyalty rewards program.
Surveys, Sweepstakes, and Message Boards. We use personal information about you, including your Identifiers and Contact Information to enable you to participate in features such as surveys, polls, sweepstakes, and message boards, where you have agreed to this. We may sometimes use a third party service provider to conduct these surveys or sweepstakes; if so, that Company will be prohibited from using your personal information for any other purpose.
Lastly, we may use information you provide to us for the following additional purposes:
Feedback. We use information you provide to us regarding our products and services to provide product feedback to our customers in aggregated form through the services.
Other Uses of Information. In addition, we may use your personal information as otherwise described to you at the time of collection with your consent.
Public Forums
Our services offer publicly accessible blogs, community forums, or reviews.
You should be aware that any information you provide in these areas may be read, collected, and used by others who access them. To request removal of your personal information from our blog or community forum, contact us at
info@nbty.com. In some cases, we may not be able to remove your personal information, in which case we will let you know if we are unable to do so and why.
Information We Share
Internal Third Parties. We are affiliated with a number of other health and wellness brands, including but not limited to American Health®, Balance®, Body Fortress®, Ester-C®, Everclen™, Nature’s Origin®, Met-Rx®, Nature’s Bounty®, Pure Protein®, Solgar®, Sundown® Naturals, Sundown® Naturals Kids, Good ‘N Natural®, Home Health™, Natural Wealth®, Flex-A-Min®, Osteo-Bi-Flex®, The Best Bar Ever®, Puritan's Pride®, Sisu®, and Dr.Organic®, all under The Nature’s Bounty Co. umbrella (collectively, our “affiliates”).
Our affiliates may share your personal information among themselves for legal purposes as well as to send you promotions, sales and offers, and newsletters in which you have indicated interest.
The subsidiary that collects your personal information will not share your personal information with other third parties for marketing purposes unless you have consented to the sharing of your information or you have indicated interest in receiving communications from third parties.
External Third Parties. We will disclose your personal information for the following limited business purposes:
Service Providers. We may share your personal information with service providers that perform certain functions or services on our behalf to fulfill the services you request from us. These include third parties that host our websites, manage databases, perform analyses, send communications for us, process payments on our behalf (e.g. Shopify), ship your orders, provide you with live chat service, or provide certain other components of our websites. Service providers are not authorized to use or disclose your personal information, except as necessary to perform services on our behalf.
Analytics.We may allow third parties to collect information in order to provide us with analytics. For instance, the services use analytics tools provided by Google to help us understand how people use the services. You can learn more about how Google collects and uses information as a part of its tools.
Protect Our Services and Users.We may disclose your personal information to governmental authorities if we believe disclosure is necessary or appropriate to prevent physical harm or financial loss, or in connection with an investigation of suspected or actual illegal activity, or violation of our website Terms of Use or other contracts.
Legal Process.We may disclose your personal information to the extent necessary to respond to subpoenas, court orders, or other legal process in response to a request for cooperation from law enforcement or a government agency, in order to comply with our other legal and regulatory obligations.
We also will share your information in the following additional circumstances:
Transactions. It may sometimes be necessary for the advancement of our legitimate commercial interests to share your personal information with our professional advisers in connection with a corporate transaction, such as a sale, assignment, divestiture, merger, bankruptcy, consolidation, reorganization, liquidation, or other transfer of the business or its assets. When we do this, we will always take measures to ensure the ongoing protection of your personal information.
Other Circumstances. We may also use your personal information in other circumstances, but we will also explain them to you at the point of collection and, where necessary, get your permission.
We Provide You Choices
You may receive marketing offers or solicitations from us through email from time to time. You can subscribe to marketing emails by emailing us at
info@nbty.com.
If you prefer not to receive marketing emails from us, please contact us at
info@nbty.com or follow the opt-out instructions at the bottom of each marketing email. Please note that these requests may take up to 10 days to be effective.
Your request not to receive marketing emails from us will not apply to messages that you request or that are not of a marketing nature. For example, we may contact you concerning any purchases you have made with us even if you opt out of receiving marketing emails.
Uploading Your Personal Information.
If you have established a user account in connection with one of our services, you may be able to review and request changes to some information that the Company maintains about you through your account settings or by contacting us at
info@nbty.com. We will respond to your request within 30 days. Upon request we will provide you with information about whether we hold any of your personal information.
Visitors from the EU may refer to the “Information Collected from Individuals in the European Union” section of this Privacy Policy for further information about your specific rights in relation to the personal information we hold about you.
Cookies and Tracking
We and our partners use cookies or similar technologies to analyze trends, administer the website, track users’ movements around the website, and to gather demographic information about our user base as a whole. We may receive reports based on the use of these technologies by these companies on an individual basis (that is, reports of your own activity) as well as on an aggregated basis (that is, reports of all user activity or of the activity of certain users as a group). Visitors from the EU may click here for additional information in the “Cookies and Tracking Technologies” section of this Privacy Policy about cookies.
You may be able to disable cookies by changing a setting in your web browser. Please note, however, that without cookies you may not be able to take full advantage of all the services’ features.
We use Local Storage, such as HTML5, to store content information and preferences. Various browsers may offer their own management tools for removing HTML5. Please note we do not currently support any browser based Do Not Track (DNT) settings or participate in any DNT frameworks, and we do not assign any meaning to any potential DNT track signals you may send or alter any of our data collection or use practices in response to such signals.
If you wish to not have your browsing information used for the purpose of serving you ads, you may opt-out by clicking here. Please note this does not opt you out of being served advertising. You will continue to receive generic ads.
Our services may be presented alongside Social Media features, such as the Facebook Like button. These features may collect your IP address, which page you are visiting on our site, and may set a cookie to enable the feature to function properly. Social Media features are either hosted by a third party or hosted directly on our services. Your interactions with these features are governed by the Privacy Policy of the company providing it.
Data Retention
We will only retain your personal information for as long as necessary (generally 7 years) to fulfill the purposes we collected it for, including for the purposes of satisfying any legal, accounting, or reporting requirements we are subject to, as well as to resolve disputes, and enforce our agreements.
If you wish to cancel your account or request that we no longer use your information to provide you services, contact us at
info@nbty.com.
Information for California Residents
Your Rights. If you are a California resident, you can take advantage of the following rights:
You may request, up to two times each year, that we disclose to you the categories and specific pieces of personal information that we have collected about you in the preceding 12 months, the categories of sources from which your personal information is collected, the business or commercial purpose for collecting your personal information, the categories of personal information that we disclosed for a business purpose or that we sold about you in the preceding 12 months, the categories of third parties with whom we have shared your personal information, and the business or commercial purpose for each sale or disclosure, if applicable.
You may request that we delete any personal information that we have collected from you.
Note that there are some reasons we will not be able to fully address your request, such as if we need to complete a transaction for you, to detect and protect against fraudulent and illegal activity, to exercise our rights, for our internal purposes, or to comply with a legal obligation.
To take advantage of any of the foregoing rights, or if you have questions about your rights, please contact us at privacy@nbty.com, 1-800-421-1168, or by mail at Nature’s Bounty Co., Legal Department, 2100 Smithtown Avenue, Ronkonkoma, New York 11779. We may take steps to verify your identity before responding to your request. If you exercise any of the foregoing rights, we will not discriminate against you, such as by denying you access to our products or restricting your access to products of certain pricing or quality. We will confirm receipt of your request within 10 business days and will respond to your request within 45 calendar days, after proper verification, unless we need additional time, in which case we will let you know.
Agent Requests. Your authorized agent may submit a request on your behalf, after submission of proof of authorization in accordance with California law. We retain the right to request confirmation directly from you confirming that the agent is authorized to make such a request or to request additional information to confirm the agent’s identity. An authorized agent is prohibited from using a consumer’s personal information, or any information collected from or about the consumer, for any purpose other than to fulfill the consumer’s requests, for verification, or for fraud prevention
Personal Information Disclosures. In the last 12 months, we disclosed the following categories of personal information for a business purpose (such as to our service providers who are restricted from using your personal information outside the scope of their services for us):
Identifiers and Contact Information, disclosed to service providers and affiliates
Commercial Information, disclosed to service providers
Health Information, disclosed to service providers
Internet/Electronic Activity Information, disclosed to service providers
We do not sell your personal information, including personal information of persons under 16 years of age.
Third Party Websites
Our services may provide links to websites operated by third parties for your convenience and information. All of these websites and applications operate independently from us, and we do not control their privacy practices. We encourage you to review the privacy policies of any third-party websites and applications that you use to better understand their privacy practices.
How We Protect Personal Information
We maintain reasonable security procedures to help protect against loss, misuse or unauthorized access, disclosure, alteration or destruction of the information you provide through our services. In addition, we limit access to your personal data to those employees, agents, contractors and other third parties who have a business need to know. They will only process your personal data on our instructions and they are subject to a duty of confidentiality.
Among other safeguards, we use Secure Sockets Layer ("SSL") technology to help protect transmissions over the internet of your payment card data.
Unfortunately, no data transmission over the internet or stored on a server can be guaranteed to be 100% secure. As a result, while we strive to protect your personal information and privacy, we cannot guarantee or warrant the security of any information you disclose or transmit to us online and cannot be responsible for the theft, destruction, or inadvertent disclosure of your personal information. If you prefer not to transmit your credit card number over the internet, you can contact us using the toll-free number listed on the website from which you want to order. If you have any questions regarding security, you can contact us at info@nbty.com.
Updates to Our Privacy Policy
We reserve the right to modify the Privacy Policy at any time. If we do this, we will post the changes on this page and will indicate at the top of this page the date those terms will be effective. We will give you advance notice of any material changes by email where possible.
It is your responsibility to check to determine if there have been changes to the Privacy Policy and to review any such changes.
Children's Privacy
Our services are not directed to persons under the age of 18. We do not knowingly collect personally identifiable information from children under 18. If a parent or guardian becomes aware that his or her child has provided us with such information without their consent, he or she should contact us via the contact details listed below. If we become aware that a child under 18 has provided us with personal information, we will delete such information from our files.
Information Collected from Individuals in the European Union
Your Rights. Under the European Union General Data Protection Regulation, you have certain rights regarding your personal information:
Right to access your information: You have the right to confirm whether and how we use your personal information, why we use it, how long we keep it, and with whom we share it. You also have the right to request a free copy of what we have.
Right to have your information shared: You have the right to request a copy of your personal information for your personal use, including sharing with other entities.
Right to rectify your information: If you believe that we hold personal information about you that is inaccurate, misleading, or incomplete, you have the right to request that we correct that information in our records.
Right to request that we remove your information: You have the right to request that we remove your personal information from our records.
Right to request that we limit use of your information: You also have the right to request that our use of your personal information be restricted.
Right to withdraw consent: Where you provide consent to our use of your personal information, you can withdraw your consent at any time by contacting us at gdprdata@nbty.com.
It may take us some time to process your request, but we will update your preferences within a reasonable period of time or inform you there will be a delay and explain why
Right to complain to a supervisory authority: Where you are unhappy with how we treat or handle your personal information, you have the right to make a complaint to the data protection supervisory authority in your home country. For example, if you live in the United Kingdom, you would contact the Information Commissioner’s Office.
If you would like to exercise any of your rights described above and submit a request, contact gdprdata@nbty.com. We will respond to all legitimate requests within one month. We may sometimes request additional information from you. Please note that we may not be able to fulfill your request under certain circumstances, such as when it is necessary to keep your information to complete an order or meet a legal obligation. If we cannot fulfill the request, we will notify you of the reasons why.
If you disagree with our resolution of your request, you have the right to make a complaint to the supervisory authority in your country. You may also seek to enforce this right through a judicial remedy.
Health Information.
We are required by law to maintain records of our customers who report adverse reactions to our dietary supplement products. We ask for your explicit consent before collecting any information about your health or medical conditions. We will use this information only for the purposes of meeting our regulatory and legal obligations and will not share it with any third parties. You may withdraw your consent at any time by contacting us as described above.
Cookies and Tracking Technologies. We and our partners use cookies or similar technologies to analyze trends, administer the website, track users’ movements around the website, and to gather demographic information about our user base as a whole. The chart below explains the different types of cookies and tracking technologies and what we use them for:
Cookie/Tracking Technology
Name
Purpose
Cookie preference
Notification_cookieconsent
GDPRCookieConsent
Where you indicate a preference about cookies on our websites, this cookie will be used to remember your choice.
Security cookies
n/a
We use these cookies to protect our legitimate interests in providing a secure shopping experience and protecting the data we hold.
Functionality cookies
ps-uid
BVImplmain_site
BVBRANDID
BVBRANDSID
We use these cookies to advance our legitimate interests in running a user-friendly website.
These recognize you when you return to the website.
For example, they help us show user reviews and where to buy our products.
Google Analytics/HotJar
_ga
_gid
_gat_
_hjIncludedInSample
We use these cookies to advance our legitimate interests in gaining insight into how our users are interacting with our websites.
These cookies are used to analyze data pertaining to our web traffic.
Add cookies
_uetsid
__atuvc
__atuvs
DSID
IDE
fr
TLTSID
TLTUID
We use these cookies to advance our legitimate interests in marketing relevant products to our customers.
These cookies are used by our third-party ad network to adapt ads to users, improve campaign effectiveness.
Web beacons
__utma
__utmc
__utmz
__utmt
__utmb
We use these cookies to advance our legitimate interests in providing relevant marketing communications.
We include web beacons in emails or newsletters to determine whether messages have been opened and identify the IP address of the computer on which they were opened.
This information helps us customize the services we offer and measure the overall effectiveness of our online content and the products and services we offer. Web beacons also allow third parties to obtain information such as the IP address of the computer that downloaded the page on which the beacon appears, the URL of the page on which the beacon appears, the time the page containing the beacon was viewed, the type of browser used to view the page, and the information in cookies set by the third party.
If you wish to not have your browsing information used for the purpose of serving you ads, you may alter your advertising preferences here.
Please note this does not opt you out of being served advertising. You will continue to receive generic ads.
EU-U.S. and Swiss-U.S. Privacy Shield
We, through our parent Company, The Nature's Bounty Co., participate in and have certified our compliance with the EU-U.S. Privacy Shield Framework and the Swiss-U.S. Privacy Shield Framework. The Company is committed to subjecting all personal data received from EU member countries, and Switzerland, respectively, in reliance on each Privacy Shield Framework, to the Framework's applicable Principles. To learn more about the Privacy Shield Frameworks, and to view our certifications, visit the U.S. Department of Commerce's Privacy Shield List here.
Under each Privacy Shield Framework, the Company is responsible for the processing of personal data it receives and subsequently transfers to a third party acting as an agent on its behalf when our agent processes such personal information in a manner inconsistent with the Privacy Shield Principles, unless the Company is not responsible for the event giving rise to the damage. The Company complies with the Privacy Shield Principles for all onward transfers of personal data from the EU and Switzerland, including the onward transfer liability provisions.
With respect to personal data received or transferred pursuant to each of the Privacy Shield Frameworks, the Company is subject to the regulatory enforcement powers of the U.S. Federal Trade Commission. In certain situations, we may be required to disclose personal data in response to lawful requests by public authorities, including to meet national security or law enforcement requirements.
If you have an unresolved privacy or data use concern that we have not addressed satisfactorily, please contact our U.S. based third party dispute resolution provider (free of charge) here.
Under certain conditions, more fully described on the Privacy Shield website you may invoke binding arbitration after other dispute resolution procedures have been exhausted.
How to Contact Us
If you have any questions or comments about this Privacy Policy, or if you would like us to update information we have about you or your preferences, please contact us by:
Email: privacy@nbty.com.
Mail:
Nature's Bounty Co.
Legal Department
2100 Smithtown Avenue
Ronkonkoma, New York 11779
If you are located in the EU, and have questions about this Privacy Policy or our privacy practices, you also may contact our EU Representative using the following contact details:
Danny Chinery
Nature’s Bounty
Beggars Lane
Aldbury, Tring
Hertfordshire
HP23 5PT
UNITED KINGDOM
+441442890355
dchinery@nbty.com
Scroll to Top
Save 10% on your next order. Sign up for our store newsletter.
Sign Up
*These statements have not been evaluated by the Food and Drug Administration. These products are not intended to diagnose, treat, cure or prevent any disease.
Use in conjunction with an intense daily exercise program and a balanced diet including an adequate caloric intake.
Always consult your doctor before beginning this or any training or diet/supplement program.
© 2019 MET-Rx Substrate Technology, Inc. & WorldPantry.com®, Inc.
We use tools, such as cookies, to provide you with the best user experience.
We use these tools to personalize content and ads, provide social media features and analyze website traffic.
Learn more or manage settings.
Accept
